Register of the Jonë Deveikë Papers, 1930-1963
Hoover Institution Archives
Jonë Deveikë Papers
1930-1963
74083
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 package (1 linear foot)
Correspondence, notes, reports, and memorabilia, relating to social and political conditions of Lithuanians in France and Germany.
Deveikë, Jonë, 1907-1965
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Biographical/Historical note
Lithuanian attorney, historian, and journalist.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, notes, reports, and memorabilia, relating to social and political conditions of Lithuanians in France and Germany.
Lithuania.; Lithuanians in foreign countries.
- BIOGRAPHICAL, MEMORABILIA, MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1930-1971 (Box 1)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1961
  - Avizonis, K., 1948
  - Babrauskas, B., 1949
  - Barenas, K., 1950
  - Bataitis, Juozas, 1960-1961
  - Ben-Gurion, 1961
  - Bohdanowicz, L., 1957-1958
  - Cecetine, Viktorija
  - Daukantas, Teodoras, 1949-1951
  - Deveikis, Vytautas, 1938-1939
  - Faculte de Droit de Paris, 1938
  - Frankel, Ernst, 1948-1950
  - Garbaciauskine, E., 1938-1939
  - Ginetis, K., 1939
  - Ivinskis, Z., 1950-1955
  - Kairelis, Alfonsas
  - Kasiulis, V., 1944
  - Kavaliunas, Jonas, 1960
  - Kiaulenas, P., 1946-1960
  - Kucas, A., 1946
  - Lappo, Ivan Ivanovich, 1936-1944
  - Lentaitis, Jonas, 1948
  - Lousse, E., 1938-1939
  - Makarsky, Alfonse, 1960-1961
  - N'Gom, Capitaine, 1939
  - Noel, A., 1938 May 22
  - Orintaite, P.
  - Raila, Bronys, 1949-1961
  - Randomanskaite, 1939
  - Roberts, D.
  - Ruzancovas, Aleksandras, 1948-1949
  - Saulys, Jurgis, 1948
  - Saulys, Prelate, 1955-1961
  - Skirpa, Kazys, 1946-1949
  - Simaite, Ona, 1948-1961
  - Soroptimist Club de Paris, 1939
  - Varnas, A., 1949
  - Vykintas, Stepas, 1949-1962
  - Zemelis, Henrikas, 1948
  - Zukauskas-Vienoulis, A., 1939
  - Miscellaneous
- SUBJECT FILE, 1930-1963 (Box 2)
  - Activities in Germany, 1944-1945
  - Certificates, passes, identification cards, etc.
  - Testimony at trial of SS Hauptsturmfuhrer Schmitz, 1963
- MISCELLANY, 1930-1960